{
    "question": "Suatu segitiga siku-siku yang panjang sisinya a 8 cm dan b 15 cm panjang sisi c nya adalah\u200b",
    "attachments": [],
    "answers": [
        {
            "answer": "<p><strong>Penjelasan:</strong></p><p><strong>Segitiga siku-siku adalah segitiga yang besar sudut pada sisi tegak lurusnya adalah 90\u00b0. Pada segitiga siku-siku berlaku teorema Pythagoras yang berbunyi besar kuadrat sisi miringnya sama dengan jumlah kuadrat dua sisi siku-sikunya.\n</strong></p><p><strong>\n</strong></p><p><strong>Ingat!!!\n</strong></p><p><strong>\n</strong></p><p><strong>Rumus teorema Pythagoras\n</strong></p><p><strong>\n</strong></p><p><strong>c\u00b2 = a\u00b2 + b\u00b2\n</strong></p><p><strong>\n</strong></p><p><strong>Diketahui:\n</strong></p><p><strong>\n</strong></p><p><strong>panjang sisi siku-siku 1 = a = 15 cm\n</strong></p><p><strong>panjang sisi siku-siku 2 = b = 8 cm\n</strong></p><p><strong>Ditanya: berapa panjang sisi miring segitiga siku-siku tersebut?\n</strong></p><p><strong>\n</strong></p><p><strong>Jawab:\n</strong></p><p><strong>\n</strong></p><p><strong>Pada soal diketahui panjang sisi siku-siku 1 = a = 15 cm dan panjang sisi siku-siku 2 = b = 8 cm\n</strong></p><p><strong>\n</strong></p><p><strong>Maka penyelesaian dari soal di atas menggunakan teorema Pythagoras.\n</strong></p><p><strong>\n</strong></p><p><strong>c\u00b2 = a\u00b2 + b\u00b2\n</strong></p><p><strong>\n</strong></p><p><strong>c\u00b2 = (15 cm)\u00b2 + (8 cm)\u00b2\n</strong></p><p><strong>\n</strong></p><p><strong>c\u00b2 = 225 cm\u00b2 + 64 cm\u00b2\n</strong></p><p><strong>\n</strong></p><p><strong>c\u00b2 = 289 cm\u00b2\n</strong></p><p><strong>\n</strong></p><p><strong>c = \u221a(289 cm\u00b2) = 17 cm\n</strong></p><p><strong>\n</strong></p><p><strong>Jadi, panjang sisi miring segitiga siku-siku yang panjang sisi siku-sikunya 15 cm dan 8 cm adalah 17 cm.\n</strong></p><p><strong>\n</strong></p><p><strong></strong></p><p></p>",
            "attachments": []
        },
        {
            "answer": "<h3>Teorema Phytagoras = </h3><ul><li>[tex] \\sqrt{ {8}^{2} }  +  {15}^{2}  = [/tex]</li><li>[tex] \\sqrt{64 + 225}  = [/tex]</li><li>[tex] \\sqrt{289}  = [/tex]</li><li>17 cm </li><li>Jadi, panjang c ( sisi miring ) = 17 cm </li></ul><p></p><h2>Semoga membantu.. Jangan dihapus jawaban saya... =)</h2><p></p>",
            "attachments": []
        }
    ],
    "related_questions": [
        {
            "slug": "andi-s-father-is-watching-tv-in-the-living-room-421",
            "question": "Andi ' s father is watching tv in the living room.",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "<p>Jawaban:</p><p>(-) Andi &#039; s father is not watching tv in the living room.</p><p>(?) is Andi &#039; s father watching tv in the living room?</p><p>Penjelasan:</p><p></p>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "ii-fill-in-the-blanks-with-the-correct-answers-16-mrs-natan-is-704",
            "question": "II.    Fill in the blanks with the correct answers\r\n16. Mrs. Natan is pretty ....... (guru)\r\n17. Diligent means in Indonesia is......\r\n18. Smart mean in Indonesia is\r\n19. Clever mean in Indonesia is\r\nA Rajin\r\nB Teacher\r\nC Pintar\r\nD Drinks\r\nE Tree\r\nF Is\r\nG GO\r\n20. She .......\r\na diligent girl\r\n21. They ........... to the library by bus\r\n22. Shinta ..........\r\n...... milk every morning\r\nH Memasak\r\n23. What can you see in the park?\r\n24. My mother likes cook\r\nI Kerja\r\nJ cerdas\r\nCook in Indonesia is .....\r\n25. My father likes go to work\r\nWork in Indonesia is .......\r\nText for question number 1-5\u200b",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "<p><strong>Jawaban:</strong></p><p>16. pretty teacher</p><p>17. rajin</p><p>18. pandai / cerdas</p><p>19. pintar</p><p>20. she is</p><p>21. went</p><p>22. drink</p><p>23. <em>ini gatau gw</em></p><p>24. memasak</p><p>25. bekerja</p><p></p><p>semoga terbantu ya\u270c</p>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "a-rabbit-aeats-carrots-and-give-wool-beats-carrots-and-giv-682",
            "question": "A rabbit .... a.eats carrots and give wool    b.eats carrots and give milk\r\nc.eats grass and gives wool \r\nd.eats carrot and gives meat \r\ntolong dijawaba\u200b",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "<p> D.eats carrot and gives meat </p><p></p><p></p><p> </p><p></p>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "number-1-and-2-refer-to-following-procedure-how-to-make-flannel-r-140",
            "question": "Number 1 and 2 refer to following procedure how to make flannel rose ring",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "<p><strong>Jawaban:</strong></p><p>Nomor 1 dan 2 lihat prosedur berikut cara membuat cincin flanel mawar:</p><p><strong>Penjelasan:</strong></p><p>Sekian semoga bermanfaat  </p>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "there-is-a-new-mature-tourism-park-in-my-town-called-panorama-ked-195",
            "question": "There is a new mature tourism park in my town called Panorama Kedah Tempunak. The park is located in Tempunak    Kapuas village. It only takes thirty minutes from my house by motorcycle to go there. It is a very big park, with colorful\r\nflowers everywhere. There are also many fruit plants, such as papayas, rambutans, rose apples, and dragon fruits. In\r\nthe middle of the park, there is a big lake. ive can explore the lake by using small duck-like boats. Next to the lake, there\r\nis a grassy landscape that makes the park looks green and fertile. The park has some outdoor benches and hammocks\r\nwhere we can sit and enjoy the view while eating snacks and drink. The park is really worth a visit.\r\n36. What can we find in Panorama Kedah Tempunak?\r\nA indoor benches\r\nB. small river\r\nC. friendly villagers\r\nD. grassy landscape\r\n37. How long does it take to go there from the writer house?\r\nA. 20 minutes\r\nB. 25 minutes\r\nC.30 minutes\r\nD. 35 minutes\r\n38 Which statement is NOT TRUE about the park based on the text above?\r\nA. There is a big lake in the middle of the park\r\nC. there are lion-shape boats in the lake.\r\nB. There are many fruit plants in the park\r\nD. the park is located in Tempunak\u200b",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "<p><strong>Jawaban:</strong></p><p>36.D</p><p>37.C</p><p>38.C</p><p><strong>Penjelasan:</strong></p><p>Sorry kalo salah:&gt;</p>",
                    "attachments": []
                },
                {
                    "answer": "<p><strong>Jawaban:</strong></p><p>nyimak iya iya iya iya iya iya iya iya iya iya iya iya iya iya iya iya iya iya iya iya iya iya iya iya iya iya iya</p>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "there-some-cute-cats-on-the-sofa-a-am-b-is-c-are-d-does-se-960",
            "question": "There____some cute cats on the sofa a. Am b. is c. are d. does\r\nsecepatnya ya\u200b",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "<p>there <u>are</u><u> </u> some cute cats on the sofa</p><p><strong>Penjelasan:</strong></p><p>c) are</p><p></p>",
                    "attachments": []
                },
                {
                    "answer": "<p>====================================</p><p>C. Are</p><p></p><h2>Pembahasan</h2><p>Untuk benda yang hanya ada 1 atau tunggal kita menggunakan \"There is\" , Sedangkan benda yang lebih dari 1 atau jamak maka kita menggunakan \"There are\". </p><p>    Maka di pertanyaan tersebut kita menggunakan \"There are\". Karena ada beberapa hewan atau pada teks tersebut dijelaskan \"some cute cats on the sofa\" yang artinya beberapa kucing lucu di sofa. </p><p>====================================</p>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "rudi-is-a-junior-high-school-student-he-goes-to-smp-13-everyday-614",
            "question": "Rudi is a junior high school student. He goes to SMP 13    everyday. He goes to school on foot (jalan kaki).\r\nRudi likes playing gootball and basket ball every week.\r\nHe never comes late to scholl. He always respects\r\n(menghormati) and obeys (mematuhi) his parents and\r\nteachers.\r\n29. Who is Rudi?\r\na. A student\r\nb. A teacher\r\nc. A player\r\nd. A football player\r\n\r\n30. Where is he studying? \r\na. SMP 12 c. SMP 14\r\nb. SMP 13 d. A football player\r\n\r\n31. How does he go to school?\r\na. By bisycle c. By bus\r\nb. By car d. on foot \r\n\r\n32. Does he like basketball? \r\na. Yes, he don't c. Yes, he does\r\nb. Yes, he liket d. Yes, he did\r\n\u200b",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "<p><strong>Jawaban:</strong></p><p>29. a. A student</p><p>30. b. SMP 3</p><p>31. d. On foot</p><p>32. c. Yes, he does</p><p><strong>Penjelasan:</strong></p><p><em>Semoga membantu..</em></p>",
                    "attachments": []
                },
                {
                    "answer": "<p><strong>Jawaban:</strong></p><p>29. A. A Student</p><p></p><p>30. B. SMP 13</p><p></p><p>31. D. On Foot</p><p></p><p>32. C. Yes, He Does</p>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "the-adorable-eyelashes-are-quality-of-animals-a-zebras-b-tiger-938",
            "question": "The adorable eyelashes, are quality of animals?    a Zebras\r\nb. Tiger\r\nc. Giraffes\r\nd. Elephants\r\n\r\nyg mana? \r\n\r\ndi follow yah \u200b",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "<p><strong>Jawaban:</strong></p><p><strong>C</strong><strong>.</strong><strong>g</strong><strong>i</strong><strong>r</strong><strong>a</strong><strong>f</strong><strong>f</strong><strong>e</strong><strong>s</strong></p><p>maaf kalau salah</p><p></p>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "the-following-statements-are-true-except-a-dewi-has-two-siste-397",
            "question": "The following statements are true, except..    a. Dewi has two sister\r\nb. Dewi always go to school early in the morning\r\nc. Lina is a diligent girl\r\nd. Dewi often visit Siti's house\u200b",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "<p><strong>Jawaban:</strong></p><p>A. Dewi has two sister</p><p><strong>Penjelasan:</strong></p><p>maaf ya kalau salah, semangat belajar nya</p><p></p>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "6-mary-reading-a-book-in-her-classroom-at-this-moment-648",
            "question": "6.) ....... Mary reading a book in her classroom at this moment?    a. Is\r\nb. am\r\nc. was\r\nd. Were\r\n\r\n7 Susan and Susanna ......... writing poems for an English cubiect now\r\na. is \r\nb. Are \r\nc. Am\r\nd. Be\r\n\r\nPliss bantu Lagi Kakak Besok ujian saya harus di kumpul\u200b",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "<p><strong>Jawaban:</strong></p><p>6.) ....... Mary reading a book in her classroom at this moment?\n</p><p><strong>a. Is</strong>\n</p><p>b. am\n</p><p>c. was\n</p><p>d. Were\n</p><p>\n</p><p>7 Susan and Susanna ......... writing poems for an English cubiect now\n</p><p>a. is\n</p><p><strong>b. Are</strong>\n</p><p>c. Am\n</p><p>d. Be</p><p>\n</p><p><strong>Penjelasan:</strong></p><p>Jawaban dicetak tebal dan menggunakan bentuk Present Continuous Tense. Nomor 6. karena subjeknya Mary, maka Tobe nya adalah a. is.</p><p>Nomor 7. karena subjeknya Susan dan Susanna, maka Tobe nya adalah b. are.</p><p>Semoga membantu ya.</p>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}